Finding Aid for the Edwin S. Shneidman Papers LSC.0385
UCLA Library Special Collections
Edwin S. Shneidman papers
1933-2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0385
37.0 linear feet (37 boxes)
Edwin S. Shneidman (1918-2009), Psychologist and Professor of Thanatology, was a leader in suicide research, or suicidology as he called it. His interest in the nature of suicide and the suicidal mental state began in the late 1940s, and he dedicated his life to understanding and prevention of suicide. Shneidman's theory of suicide was based on his idea of psychological pain he termed "psychache." His theories are vastly influential in today's suicide research and prevention. Shneidman founded the Los Angeles Suicide Prevention Center in 1955, developed a national suicide prevention center program with the NIMH in the 1960s, and authored 20 books and hundreds of articles. In 1987 Shneidman received the American Psychological Association Award for Distinguished Contributions to Public Service. The collection contains research files on suicide, restricted patient information, correspondence, related audio-visual materials, and a small collection of Herman Melville ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research, with the exception of materials protected under HIPAA or for which there is sensitive health information in Series 1: Biographical, Series 2: Correspondence, Series 5: Professional and Academic Activities, and Series 8: Suicide Research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
In order to access materials that are protected under HIPAA (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act) or for which there is sensitive health information, please submit a research protocol to Library Special Collections at speccoll@library.ucla.edu.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edwin Shneidman, 2009.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9969302983606533
Biographical History
Edwin S. Shneidman (1918-2009), Psychologist and Professor of Thanatology, was a leader in suicide research, or suicidology as he called it. His interest in the nature of suicide and the suicidal mental state began in 1949. He found hundreds of suicide notes in the Los Angeles County Coroner's office while researching two cases. The rest of his life was dedicated to the understanding and prevention of suicide. Shneidman held appointments at Harvard, the National Institutes of Mental Health, the Center for Advanced Studies of Behavioral Science at Stanford, and at UCLA. His theory of suicide was based on the notion that there is a threshold of mental/emotional pain upon which some individuals come to feel that cessation of life is the one and only solution. Shneidman termed this pain "psychache," and could be researched without resorting to biological or genetic causation. Shneidman concluded that most suicidal individuals, while in the fatal suicidal state, are ambivalent about dying and can be saved. His theories are vastly influential in today's suicide research and prevention.
Shneidman became the first Professor of Thanatology at UCLA in 1970 and remained a full-time professor there until 1988. Shneidman also founded the Los Angeles Suicide Prevention Center in 1955, with Norman Farberow and Robert E. Litman. In 1966, he was asked to develop a national suicide prevention center program at the NIMH. Shneidman authored 20 books and hundreds of articles. Shneidman believed that suicidology should be about the understanding of the whole individual. He developed the "psychological autopsy," a method of figuring out an equivocal death, or a retrospective investigation of the intention of the decedent. Shneidman also believed that post-vention, the treatment of an attempted-suicide and the suicide's family, was just as important as prevention and intervention.
In the late 1960s, Shneidman founded the American Association of Suicidology and its journal, Suicide and Life Threatening Behavior. As an internationally recognized scholar on suicide and suicide prevention, he was active in developing suicide or life-threatening behavior prevention programs in various centers at UCLA, as well as in Japan. In 1987 Shneidman received the American Psychological Association Award for Distinguished Contributions to Public Service.
As a fan of Herman Melville, Edwin Shneidman wrote extensively on the suicidal connections in Melville's life and his writings, such as Moby Dick. Shneidman was a member of the Herman Melville Society and donated his Melville Collection to UCLA in the late 1980s. Shneidman's personal collection contains left over Melville ephemera and related correspondence with the Melville Society and Shneidman's work on Melville.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains research on suicide, including restricted materials on suicidal patients, professional and personal correspondence, documents related to Shneidman's professional responsibilities, literature authored by Shneidman, and documents and correspondence related to Herman Melville. There are several boxes containing audio-visual materials of transcripts, radio and television appearances, patient conversations, and a NIMH suicide training manual.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Biographical
Series 2: Correspondence
Series 3: ESS Publications
Series 4: Herman Melville Documents
Series 5: Professional and Academic Activities
Series 6: Reference Materials
Series 7: Suicide Prevention Centers
Series 8: Suicide Research
Separated Materials
Items removed from the collection include non-Shneidman personnel files, empty folders, duplicate files, and reprinted publications.
Thanatologists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Suicide -- Research -- Archives.; Book collectors -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Shneidman, Edwin S. --Archives.
- Biographical, Series 1.
  Conditions Governing Access
  In order to access materials that are protected under HIPAA (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act) or for which there is sensitive health information, please submit a research protocol to Library Special Collections at speccoll@library.ucla.edu.
  - Biographies, CVs, Bibliographies, Obituaries (1 of 2) -- Restricted., 1977-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographies, CVs, Bibliographies, Obituaries (2 of 2) -- Restricted., 1988-1992. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Autobiographical notes and personal papers -- Restricted., 1962-1984. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Autobiographical notes and personal missives -- Restricted., 1965-1982. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abraham Lincoln High School notes, Los Angeles, CA -- Restricted., 1933-1934. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Autobiography Pictures -- Restricted., 1910-1988. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pictures and song from Dana & Joel -- Restricted., December 1987. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Shneidman and other colleagues -- Restricted., 1950-1981. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ESS - USC payroll and insurance information -- Restricted., 1965. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Board for Psychological Services, certificate and correspondence -- Restricted., 1954-1959. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Autobiography, "A Life in Death: Notes of a Committed Suicidologist, An Epistolary Autobiography" - Work Copy -- Restricted., 1990. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Autobiography, "A Life in Death" manuscript with photos -- Restricted., 1989-1991. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Autobiography, "A Life in Death" published copy and copies of letters from Henry A. Murray -- Restricted., undated. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Dear Impossibility: An Epistolary Autobiography of a Suicidologist" - Draft -- Restricted., undated. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notes and correspondence regarding autobiography -- Restricted., 1989. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence regarding autobiography -- Restricted., 1989-1991. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Wisconsin Press correspondence regarding autobiography -- Restricted., 1999. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Autobiographical chapter in "A History of Clinical Psychology in Autobiography," Edited by C. Eugene Walker, PhD. -- Restricted., 1990. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Irv Bernstein's Power of Attorney -- Restricted., 1990. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Weekly Calendars, 1960s -- Restricted., 1961-1969. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    1962 and 1964 missing.
  - Weekly Calendars, 1970s -- Restricted., 1970-1979. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    1973 is missing.
  - Weekly Calendars, 1980s (1 of 2) -- Restricted., 1980-1985. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Weekly Calendars, 1980s (1 of 2) -- Restricted., 1986-1989. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Weekly Calendars, 1990s -- Restricted., 1990-1999. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    1998 is missing.
  - Personal journal / Diary, miscellaneous., undated. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "A Macrotemporal View of My Life" and photographs of ESS and colleagues at Melville Reception at UCLA., 1991 and 2007. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1967 Diary, handwritten notes. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - High school work., 1930s. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ideas from my Undergraduate Years: An Autobiographical Fragment., 2001. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, Series 2.
  - Letters of reference re: psychology appointment in Navy., 1941-1942. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Official correspondence regarding World War II service., 1942-1945. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence regarding WWII service., 1941-1947. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rolodex cards, alphabetical A-R (1 of 2)., undated. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rolodex cards, alphabetical S-Z (2 of 2)., undated. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1950-1967. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Harvard Yard, notes., 1960s. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Alport - White., 1962-1963. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Watson, John B. / C.A. Larson., 1963. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Suicide & Self-Destruction., 1964-1965. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Logic" Correspondence and reprints., 1964. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Dublin, Dr. Louis., 1964-1965. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Iga, Mamoru., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Publishers, Essays in Self-Destruction., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Contributors, Essays in Self-Destruction., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Uncategorized correspondence 1966. (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., Earle T. Dewey, MD, San Francisco., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1963. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - MS: Suicide and Death in Japan, A Personal Report, Int'l Journal of Psychiatry., 1965 August. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Suicide and Death in Japan: A Personal Report, ESS 1965. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Japan Trip: KGS., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Dr. Stanley Plog: Cognitive Maneuvers: McCarthy., 1965 October 1. (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Japan., 1964-1965. (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Japanese Suicide Prevention Center Activities., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Japan Contacts and lectures., 1965 April. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Japan, Key Persons., undated. (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Book Review: DJ West's "Murder Followed by Suicide"., 1966 April 1. (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Travel, Janet G. and Shur, Max., 1967. (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Korengold, Susan G., 1967. (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Lethality, Suicide: Symptom of., 1967. (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Suicidology, Bulletin of - notes on., 1967-1968. (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Ohara, Kenshiro Dr., 1967-1968. (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - World Health Organization., 1967. (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Dr. Robert Blauner, Sociologist; UCB correspondence and "Death and Social Structure: A Functional Analysis"., 1967 March and June. (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Amrine, Michael., 1964. (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Japanese visitors to LASPC., 1965-1966. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - C.S.S.S. Denis O'Donovan., 1967-1968. (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - C.S.S.S. Henle, Mary Dr., 1967-1968. (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - William E. Bunny, Jr., MD; HEW: Biochemical Test for Suicidal Potential (pamphlet and magazine clipping)., 1959 and 1966. (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - University of Southern California, School of Medicine., 1963-1966. (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Plog, Stanley C., 1965. (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Suicide Prevention Activities in other areas., 1960 - 1964. (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - "On Suicide"., 1967-1969. (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Uncategorized correspondence., 1969. (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Henry A. Murray (HAM) correspondence., 1949-1988. (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - HAM LTRS., undated. (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - ESS-HAM in Chron order, still to be cued., 1962-1984. (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - HAM miscellaneous correspondence., 1960s-1987. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Murray, Henry A transcripts of letters., 1949-1973. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Murray, Henry A letters and related., 1962-1988. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Murray, Henry A photocopies of letters to ESS and related., 1952-1973. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding HAM., 1973 April 19-20. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Murray, Henry A Interview., 1983. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Reflections on HAM., 1986. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - HAM Leaves of Green Memories., 1963. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Murray - Personal correspondence., 1978-1979. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - H & C correspondence., 1967-1990. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - HAM at 80., 1973-1982. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - HAM at 90 - tape transcript., undated. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - HAM at 90 - transcript., 1983 October 12. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Murray, Henry A. Address in LA., 1963. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - "Ruth and Richard letters - my sister Eileen" and "Bransten letters" - 1950s., 1974. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Veterans Association., 1970. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence May 1971 through August 1971., 1971 May-August. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence May 1971 through January 1972., 1971 May - 1972 January. (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous re: Szasz' "The Ethics of Suicide"., 1971-1972. (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Thomas Szasz materials and photographs from 1972 debate., 1972-1976. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Audiotape recordings of debate are located in Box
  - Correspondence January 1972 through May 1972., 1972 January-May. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence May 1972 through November 1972 (1 of 2)., 1972 May-November. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence May 1972 through November 1972 (2 of 2)., 1972 May-November. (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence December 1972 through January and February 1973 (1 of 2)., 1972 December - 1973 February. (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence December 1972 through January and February 1973 (2 of 2)., 1972 December - 1973 February. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence March 1973 through June 1973 (1 of 2)., 1973 March-June. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence March 1973 through June 1973 (2 of 2)., 1973 March-June. (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence July and August 1973., 1973 July-August. (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - September 20 through October 31, 1973., 1973 September 20 - 1973 October 31. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence from January 1971 through April 1971., 1971 January-April. (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence from November 1973 through December 1973., 1973 November-December. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from January 1974 through February 1974., 1974 January-February. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from March 1974 through April 1974., 1974 March-April. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from April 1974 to August 1974., 1974 April-August. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence October 1974., 1974 October. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence November 1974., 1974 November. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence December 1974., 1974 December. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence January 1975., 1975 January. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - February Correspondence 1975., 1975 February. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - March 1975 Correspondence., 1975 March. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - April Correspondence 1975., 1975 April. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - May 1975 Correspondence., 1975 May. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - June 1975 Correspondence., 1975 June. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - July 1975 Correspondence., 1975 July. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - August 1975 Correspondence., 1975 August. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - September 1975 Correspondence., 1975 September. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - October 1975 Correspondence., 1975 October. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - November Correspondence 1975., 1975 November. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - December Correspondence 1975., 1975 December. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Translation., 1974. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous letters received 1974-1975. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Pasnal letter & R.A., 1975 November 20. (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - LTB (Life Threatening Behavior Journal)., 1970. (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - UCLA., 1970. (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, September through December 1970., 1970 September-December. (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - US Navy 1971. (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - University's Response to Unusual Death., 1972. (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous ca. 1973. (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous notes & correspondence., 1975-1976. (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence January 1976., 1976 January. (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - February 1976 Correspondence., 1976 February. (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - March 1976 Correspondence., 1976 March. (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - April 1976 Correspondence., 1976 April. (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - May Correspondence 1976., 1976 May. (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - June Correspondence 1976., 1976 June. (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - July 1976 Correspondence., 1976 July. (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - August 1976 Correspondence., 1976 August. (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - September 1976 Correspondence., 1976 September. (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - October 1976 Correspondence., 1976 October. (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - November Correspondence 1976., 1976 November. (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - December 1976 Correspondence., 1976 December. (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence., 1976. (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - January 1977 Correspondence., 1977 January. (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence February 1977., 1977 February. (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - March 1977 Correspondence., 1977 March. (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - April 1977 Correspondence., 1977 April. (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - May 1977 Correspondence., 1977 May. (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - June 1977 Correspondence., 1977 June. (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - July 1977 Correspondence., 1977 July. (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - August 1977 Correspondence., 1977 August. (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - September 1977 Correspondence., 1977 September. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - October Correspondence 1977., 1977 October. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - November 1977 Correspondence., 1977 November. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence December 1977., 1977 December. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence January 1978., 1978 January. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence February 1978., 1978 February. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence March 1978., 1978 March. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence April 1978., 1978 April. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - May Correspondence 1978., 1978 May. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence June 1978., 1978 June. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence July 1978., 1978 July. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence August 1978., 1978 August. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence September 1978., 1978 September. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence October 1978., 1978 October. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence November 1978., 1978 November. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence December 1978., 1978 December. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - UCLA Memos., 1976-1977. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1975-1977. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Requests for reprints and thanatology info., 1974-1978. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Letters of Recommendation., 1975-1978. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Jan 1979., 1979 January. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Feb 1979., 1979 February. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Mar 1979., 1979 March. (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Apr 1979., 1979 April. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - May 1979., 1979 May. (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - November '79., 1979 November. (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - December '79., 1979 December. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Takumitsu & Sachiko Shirai., 1979. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Endeavors in Psychology 1979 Correspondence. (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Nobel Committee., 1972 and 1976. (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - APA Distinguished Award winners (Division 12)., 1979. (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Bio - Lois Ames., 1979-1981. (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding Mensa suicides., 1969-1970. (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence 1971-1987. (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous publications, announcements, book reviews, correspondence., 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (1 of 5)., 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (2 of 5)., 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (3 of 5)., 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (4 of 5)., 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (5 of 5)., 1970s. (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - HAM - ESS key., 1950-1973. (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - HAM letters (photocopies)., 1967-1981. (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Murray: Letters 1-27 (photocopies)., 1949-1961. (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Murray: Letters 28-76 (photocopies)., 1962-1966. (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Murray: Letters 77-117 (print-outs)., 1967-1972. (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Murray: Letters 118- (no end number)., 1973. (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - HAM letters (photocopies)., 1949-1983. (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - HAM Obit, includes Christiana Drummond Morgan., 1962-1988. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Nobel, copies of ESS-HAM., 1961-1972. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Study of Lines., 1962-1963. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: ESS - Personal., 1962-1975. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Complimentary memos., 1979-1981. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Division 12 Awards., 1978-1979. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Biography, ESS - Lois Ames., 1978-1979. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Daniel Warner, "Our Time to Die"., undated. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - ES Correspondence [to ES]., 1976 and 1986. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence re: Endeavor., 1979-1980. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hildreth Award., 1966 September 6. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ellis Island., 1970-1972. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Includes a 1905 National Geographic journal on immigration.
  - Diaries: Misc. Correspondence., 1979-1981. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Personal correspondence., 1967-1969. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Correspondence., 1968-1985. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - HAM letters (1 of 2)., 1955-1985. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - HAM letters (2 of 2)., 1955-1985. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Murray-Radcliffe., 1981. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Endeavors at Harvard., 1981 April 7. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Suicide thoughts and reflections., 1980 and 1981. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Quiet Cries and transcript., 1969 April 11. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Voices of Death: Japanese, Hebrew, Swedish., 1980. (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Voices of Death: Permissions., ca. 1978-1980. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Voices of Death: Approvals- Originals from publishers' notes and charts (1 of 2)., ca. 1978-1980. (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Voices of Death: Approvals- Originals from publishers' notes and charts (2 of 2)., ca. 1978-1980. (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Loma Feigenberg Correspondence., 1978-1980. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Voices of Death: uncategorized correspondence., 1980. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous speaking engagements., 1982-1983. (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - January 1980., 1980 January. (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - February 1980., 1980 February. (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - March 1980., 1980 March. (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - April 1980., 1980 April. (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - May 1980., 1980 May. (Box 11, Folder 33)